Development of Process Capability Baselines
Welcome back to this session on baselines.
Specifically in this segment, we're going to be looking at the idea of a quality baseline.
Now, to begin to understand how we're going to look at quality.
We can measure quality on any number of different dimensions,
but specifically the one we’re going to look at is the idea of sigmas.
How many sigmas is your process?
Okay, now what is a Sigma?
A sigma. in a statistical sense, is like a ruler.
Now, here comes the question, if I have variation,
how can I measure variation?
How can I quantify the extent of variation that's present?
Let's say for example, I go out and I produce a bunch of lines.
There's the lines I produce. I can now put a ruler on there and measure those lines.
Like, there's about a half-inch. There’s about three quarters of an inch.
There's about one inch. There's approximately two inches.
There is approximately 1.25 inches.
And there’s about 1.5 inches. Well, that's actually about 1.5 too.
Now as you can see, I have variations in those measurements.
So, how much variation is present?
Well, for variation we don't have things like an inch,
a pound, miles per hour.
We don't have that kind of standard. What we do have is a concept called
the standard deviation.
For any given set of data we compute the standard deviation.
Just like this, we can take that set of data and compute the standard deviation.
So for that set of data, it's a standard amount,
or the typical deviation that exists here. So that makes it like an inch or a pound.
But only for that set of data. So, it's like a standard.
Now, here's the way the sigmas works. We gotta switch concept here.
Let's imagine that we are measuring IQ.
Intelligence quotient, how smart somebody is.
So, I go out into the world and I give an exam to a lot of people to measure IQ.
So, here's a scale of IQ. And I find that the average is about 100.
Well, I can come over here and count the number of people with an IQ, say between
say between 102 and 98. So, that's 102 and that's 98.
And I can make a bar, that corresponds to the height of the number of people
that I was able to
find with an IQ between 102 and 98.
Then I can go over here and say, between 102 and 106.
And count the number of people.
Once again, that makes a height of a bar.
I could come on the other side of that, between, say, 98 and 94.
And count the number of people. See, that would fill in.
So if I kept doing that, for those intervals of size four
what I would wind up with is a graph.
That have fewer, and fewer, and fewer people
as you head over here toward Einstein's way. And the same thing would hold true,
as my kids would say, as you head over here in my direction.
Now of course there's no absolute zero point here. We’re just throwing that in.
Well my kids, would of course disagree with that.  But nonetheless we call this a histogram.
Now, if I take and identify
the midpoint of each interval here. And interconnect those
with a smooth curve,
we’re left with this bell-shaped thing, that looks like a bell.
Now, I'm going to redraw that, because that bell
is what we call the normal distribution.
Things like IQ, our hair thickness, the height of people, the weight of people.
Many things naturally distribute themselves, in this world, as a bell curve.
Or as the normal distribution, as many say.
Now what we’re going to do, is we're going to come back and visit this idea
of the normal distribution and how it plays in with the quality baseline.
For right now we're going to just absorb what we just took a look at,
by considering one last graph. And that's a characteristic out in the process.
And you can see that in this case, we have a range between 130 and 70.
Maybe that's the diameter of a shaft.
Or maybe that's the amount of seconds
to respond to a customer in a commercial application.
But here's some actual data and we can see how that
curve would fit to this histogram.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.